MOHAMED ISHAQ ISMAIL

C-wing, Flat No.:503, Sai Swar C.H.S., Sector-2, Plot No.:20, Kharghar, Navi Mumbai - 410210 0091 9894681900 ishaqismail7210@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

With having more than 4+ years of experience as Design Engineer. Seeking a responsible career position, which will offer a high level of challenge, responsibility and opportunity to contribute significantly to the growth of the organization with experience on costing and administration as well as develop additional skills.

EDUCATION

Jain University
M.Tech (Aerospace - Structure)

2015

71%

Vel Tech Technical University.

2013

B.Tech (Aeronautical)

79%

EXPERIENCE

Hettich Compentence Services PVT. LTD., Mumbai

August 2018 - Present

CAD Engineer

Designing of 2D and 3D model of furniture hardware like Hinges, Drawer Runner, Drawer Sets. Handles etc using SolidWorks.

Incorport the hardware a furniture software like imos.

Forte Furniture Products India PVT. LTD., Chennai

August 2017 - August 2018

Design Engineer

Designing on 2D & 3D model of home & office furniture in all ranges, R&D of costume made design for client, NPD as per costumer requirement from starch, BOM generation, sample fabrication, material follow up and on field inspection of pilot product etc. Special HARDWARE development in Plastics & Metal using Solid Work and AUTOCAD. Uploading DATA & PDM in SAP

HCL Technologies (SourceOne), Chennai

October 2016 - May 2017

Design Engineer

Responsible for Medical Device based CAD drawings, Sheet Blank designing, Mechanical offers, 3D drawing generation at Solid Work and CATIA along with Medical Device Documents, BOM generation, sample fabrication, customer Design follow ups etc.

EELGRASS ENGINERING SERVICE PVT. LTD., Coimbatore

May 2015 - October 2016

Design Engineer

Responsible for 3D Models, Individual part drawings, Surface Modelling, Sheet Metal, Assembly, Detailing, Drafting, Customer follow ups, BOM generations, 3D development drawings, project handling, sample fabrications, Designing on 2D &

3D model of heavy automobile components, R&D of costume made heavy vehicles, material follow up and on field inspection of pilot product etc.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

R&D

Design Concept ProtoTyping

Modifying Design and Re-Testing

CAD Software - AutoCAD, Solidworks, Catia, Creo 2.0, IMOS iX, wCC.

CAM Software - IMOS CAM, Hyper-Mesh.

Design Calculations Special Purpose Machine Special Hardware Design ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS

Boost up the Prototype drawing from 12% to 35% by using CAD software Solidworks with mimimum level of error in Forte Furniture India Products LTD.

Got 1st promotion at very short time span on performance basis in EELGRASS ENGINEERING SERVICE PVT LTD., Coimbatore,

PERSONAL PROFILE

Date of Birth : 04th Dec. 1990

Marital Status : Married
Nationality : INDIAN

Known Languages : English, Hindi, Tamil & Marathi

Passport : Z 4350933

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above mentioned details are true to the best of my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the stated particulars.

MOHAMED ISHAQ ISMAIL